Contact

9639170897 (Home) ayushporwalrock7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/aayushporwal-88840b185 (LinkedIn) www.facebook.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Analytical Skills
Business Data Management
Predictive Analytics

Languages

English (Professional Working) Hindi (Full Professional)

Publications

Ecosystem

Primary key, Foreign key and Candidate key in SQL

Aayush Porwal

DATA ANALYTICS|Data Science & Analytics- SQL, Python, Hypothetical analysis, predictive analysis| Data Modelling Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

Summary

Data Analyst with over 2 years of experience in the field of data science & analytics, accompanied by a bachelor's degree in B.S.C Computer Science. My professional journey has spanned diverse sectors like edtech, e-commerce, and IT where I use my skills in making predictions and hypotheses to make the business profitable.

I am well versed with tools like powerbi and database language SQL. I have also basic knowledge of MS Office. I excel in Data cleaning, data processing, data analysis, data visualization, and making reports. Also, I used insights to solve problems using Microsoft Excel.

I did my Bachelor of Science & communication in Computer Science, Physics, and Mathematics 2015 from Dr Bhim Rao Ambedkar University. I acquired a diploma in Computer application.

Key Skills: Data science, Data analytics, Statistical analysis, Hypothesis Testing, Predictive Analytics, Problem Solving Languages: SQL, Python, HTML

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, MySQL,

SQLite

Other: Excel, AWS Cloud, Google Cloud, Git, Web Analytics and

Google Analytics.

Also, a Content Creator & Educator with vast experience of more than 5 years in content writing and SEO. Creating content is my passion to educate others.

▶# YouTube Channel link: www.youtube.com/

@sourceforaspirants5588

Github profile: https://github.com/aayushporwal

mail: ayushporwalrock7@gmail.com

Medium- https://medium.com/@ayushporwalrock7

Experience

Paper Packers

Data Analyst

August 2022 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Agra, Uttar Pradesh, India

I am Working as a Data Analyst here. My skills that contribute to this role are Excel and PowerBI mainly. I daily fetch the data of clients who make orders. I made monthly, Quarterly, and yearly reports in Excel and prepared the Dashboard charts using Excel and Power BI to make profitable decisions for the company.

I also assist in generating GST bills and maintaining sales and purchase data of clients.

GeeksforGeeks

Content Specialist

May 2022 - August 2024 (2 years 4 months)

Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

SEO content writing, SEO content optimization, Technical content writing

Testbook

Associate SME

July 2022 - August 2022 (2 months)

Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

My work in the company includes the

Worked as a content writer,

Making quizzes and mocks for government Exam

Curate content of freelancers.

To collaborate with freelancers and to check the quality of content

Respond to the queries on the Portal

Making quizzes daily, weekly, and on an exam basis.

I have strongholds in state category exams like PCs and also for one-day exams.

Doubtnut

5 months

Senior Content Writer

December 2021 - March 2022 (4 months)

Gurugram

Content Developer

November 2021 - March 2022 (5 months)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

My work includes collaborating with educators to make live lecture content and exam notes optimising the content using HTML and translating it into Hindi too.

pariksha adda

2 years 10 months

Subject Matter Expert

October 2020 - March 2022 (1 year 6 months)

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

Education Professional

June 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

The MindEcademy

Subject Matter Expert

April 2020 - April 2021 (1 year 1 month)

creative web content writing for coding and optimising content with HTML. writing blogs to support thier website to support the customer to visit the company pages. making content on Homepage, overview, contact us page etc. Optimise content using SEO and providing content to different stakeholders based on Sql, python and for academics.

createforus

Subject Matter Expert

August 2020 - January 2021 (6 months)

India

MAD EDUCATORS

Content Developer

April 2020 - December 2020 (9 months)

India

Education

Dr. Bhim Rao Ambedkar University

Bachelor of science and communication, Computer Science · (2013 - 2015)

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (NIELIT)

Course on Computer Concepts, ccc course · (2018 - 2018)

Mahatma Gandhi Montessory Senior Secondary School intermediate CBSE board, science · (2012 - 2013)

Mahatma Gandhi Montessory Senior Secondary School high school CBSE board · (2009 - 2010)

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (NIELIT)

Diploma in tally